Developer @ Innovation labs

sidharthe38943@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Innovative tech mind with 1.6 years of experience working as a computer programmer. Capable of working with a variety of technology and software solutions, and managing databases. Valuable team member who has experience diagnosing problems and developing solutions. Talented person with unique ideas and a history of successful contributions in the field.

CONTACT

Shasta Nilayam, km Challa, Eduppukulam(Po) Palakkad, Kerala Pincode 678556 6238471816 Indian

DOB: 07/07/1999 Marital Status: Single

SKILLS

Asp.net

C#

Azure

Python

web technologies (HTML,CSS,Js)

Vue.js

Django

MySQL

LANGUAGES

Malayalam

English

Tamil

Hindi

STRENGTHS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SRE

TCS

18/01/2021 - 01/06/2022

Chennai

Site reliability engineers sit at the crossroads of traditional IT and software development. SRE teams are made up of software engineers who build and implement software to improve the reliability of their systems

Developer

TCS

06/06/2022 - Present

chennai

Developer at TCS innovation lab .TCS has a global network of innovation labs, classified as technology labs, academic alliance labs and domain labs. The labs create differentiators and build innovation capabilities for TCS's businesses, helping its customers with innovation across different time zones.

EDUCATION

Vlb Janakiammal College of Arts and Science

BCA

17/07/2017 - 21/09/2020

Grade - 78%

Coimbatore

Bachelor in Computer Application (BCA) is an undergraduate degree course in computer applications. The duration of the course is 3 years and divided into 6 semesters. It comprises of the subjects like database, networking, data structure, core programming languages like 'C' and 'java'.

PROJECTS

1. Host override testing

Tool is created as part of SRE automation .The tool is created using c# and selenium which will check the overall response time of the web page and will calculate the performance of the web site.

Technology used: asp.net and c#

2. Python voice assistant bot

A personal assistant using python which can perform various actions based on voice commands like sending email, surfing on web, mathematical calculation, playing music, opening files, etc

Technology used: Python

3. Daily Expense Tracker

"DAILY EXPENSE TRACKER" is a project which pro-

poses to form a process that can help to store and retrieve details regarding the expense of a person or an organazation. My project has several modules which are, login Dashboard. It can generate various reports as per requirements. It follows the two- tier architecture with front-end php and back-end SQL Server. My project is capable of generating exepense report based on months ,year aswell as days

Technology used:PHP, mysql

4.Individual household electric power consumption Data Set Performed various techniques in data set and created model

• Data exploration and analysis.

Dedication Hardworking

Strong Work Ethic Punctuality

Listening skills

Analytical and Problem Solving Skills

INTERESTS

Software development

Web development AI/ML

• Regression and Time's

Data Visualization.

• Regression and Time series analysis.

· Frequency Domain Analysis.

Technology used: Python

5. Mask detection

A deep learning based model for detecting masks over faces in public place to curtail community spread of Coronavirus is presented. The proposed model efficiently handles varying kinds of occlusions in dense situation by making use of ensemble of single and two stage detectors. The ensemble approach not only helps in achieving high accuracy but also improves detection speed considerably. The model is 98.2% accurate at mask detection with averagein-ference times of 0.05 seconds per image

Technology used: Python

6.SL triage tool

This project is created as part of SRE automation. The tool is created using asp.net . The functionality of tool is to fetch required details of member from database and api . This details will be further used to validate overall account setup and will display the result .

Technology used :Asp.net ,C#, MySql

6.Akaname report genarator

The tool is created aspart of SRE automation. The tool is created to cross verify the data from vendor with data from database. The verified data report will be automatically send to vendor mail.

Technology used: C#

7.Infra prediction

The application is created as part of innovation team project. The application motive is predict the snowday tickets count and categorize the tickets by training the data pulled from Snowday using SARIMA model and deployed the model in application created using django.

Technology used: Django framework and python